export const GOVERNMENTA2000 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The arm of government responsible for the making of laws is the",
A: "executive",
B: "Judiciary",
C: "legislature",
D: "press",
answer: "C. legislature",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The fundamental law of a state which provides the principles upon which a government is established is the",
A: "manifesto",
B: "decree",
C: "rule of law",
D: "constitution",
answer: "D. constitution",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The body that drafts a new constitution for a state is the",
A: "national assembly",
B: "constituent assembly",
C: "Judicial service",
D: "parliamentary",
answer: "B. constituent assembly",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The movement which was formed to protest against the Land Bill of 1897 in Ghana was the",
A: "Aborigines’ Rights Protection Society.",
B: "West Africa Students Union",
C: "Fante Confederation",
D: "National Congress of British West Africa",
answer: "A. Aborigines’ Rights Protection Society",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The boycott of European goods in Ghana as result of high prices was organized in 1918 by",
A: "Kwame Nkrumah",
B: "Modesto Apaloo",
C: "Baafuour Osei Yaw Akoto",
D: "Nii Kobina Eonne 11",
answer: "D. Nii Kobina Eonne II",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The body set up by the colonial government to investigate the 1948 political disturbances in Ghana was the",
A: "Coussey Committee",
B: "Watson Committee",
C: "Frederick Bourne Commission",
D: "Greenwood commission",
answer: "B. Watson Committee",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Aristocracy is government",
A: "privileged class",
B: "Mass of the people",
C: "military junta",
D: "group of mercenaries",
answer: "A. privileged class",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The transfer of some aspects of law making to other bodies is referred to as",
A: "power transfer",
B: "regulatory measures",
C: "delegated legislation",
D: "ultra vires",
answer: "C. delegated legislation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The administration of Justice in a state is the responsibility of the",
A: "police",
B: "legislature",
C: "judiciary",
D: "executive",
answer: "C. judiciary",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The electorate vote for their representatives through",
A: "elections",
B: "gerrymandering",
C: "electioneering campaign",
D: "demagogy",
answer: "A. elections",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following was not an aspect of the French policy of assimilation?",
A: "Economic integration of the colonies with the metropolis.",
B: "Ruling the citizens and subjects through the chiefs",
C: "Representation of Africans in the Chamber of Deputies",
D: "Treating the educated Africans as Frenchmen",
answer: "B. Ruling the citizens and subjects through the chiefs",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The highest court of justice for Ghana during the colonial period was the",
A: "Supreme Court",
B: "High Court",
C: "West African Court of Appeal",
D: "Judicial Committee of the Privy Council",
answer: "D. Judicial Committee of the Privy Council",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Freedom of religion in a state presupposes that",
A: "the church controls the state",
B: "the church is state-controlled",
C: "all citizens practise one religion",
D: "individual can practise any religion of their choice",
answer: "D. individual can practise any religion of their choice",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The idea by which civil servants are supposed to be politically unbiased in their work is known as",
A: "political neutrality",
B: "consciousness",
C: "independence",
D: "opportunity",
answer: "A. political neutrality",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The French policy of assimilation in West Africa was a system of",
A: "decentralization",
B: "delegated Legislation",
C: "direct rule",
D: "indirect rule",
answer: "C. direct rule",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The form of government advocated by the Supreme Military Council ( S.M.C) I was",
A: "parliamentary government",
B: "union government",
C: "presidential government",
D: "unitary government",
answer: "B. union government",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following countries is not a permanent member of the Security Council of the United Nations Organization?",
A: "Russia",
B: "France",
C: "Britain",
D: "Germany",
answer: "D. Germany",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. In a federation, the following powers of government can be allocated to the centre and the units except",
A: "enumerated powers",
B: "arbitrary powers",
C: "concurrent powers",
D: "residuary powers",
answer: "B. arbitrary powers",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The concentration of power in the hands of one political leader often leads to",
A: "dictatorship",
B: "democracy",
C: "socialism",
D: "capitalism",
answer: "A. dictatorship",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. An alien may secure the citizenship of a country by",
A: "nationalization",
B: "immunization",
C: "naturalization",
D: "birth",
answer: "C. naturalization",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The main duty of the committees of the legislature is to",
A: "approve the laws enacted by the parent body",
B: "expedite the legislative process",
C: "enforce the laws",
D: "interpret the laws",
answer: "B. expedite the legislative process",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Membership of the Commonwealth of Nations is exclusively for",
A: "countries of the former British Empire",
B: "French colonial territories",
C: "European Economic Community members",
D: "independent African States",
answer: "A. countries of the former British Empire",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. An individual who has any of his rights trampled upon can enforce those rights through",
A: "a committee of the legislature",
B: "the law reform committee",
C: "the courts of law of the land",
D: "the national house of chiefs",
answer: "C. the courts of law of the land",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following is not a duty of a citizen of the state?",
A: "Enlistment in the national army",
B: "Complete obedience to the laws of the state",
C: "Payment of taxes at the appropriate time",
D: "Interference with other citizens’ rights",
answer: "D. Interference with other citizens’ rights",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The concept which stipulates that the functions of government should be performed by three different groups of people is",
A: "checks and balances",
B: "rule of law",
C: "separation of powers",
D: "judicial review",
answer: "C. separation of powers",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. In a democratic government, legal sovereignty resides in the",
A: "legislature",
B: "electorate",
C: "judiciary",
D: "executive",
answer: "A. legislature",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The Convention People’s Party ( C.P.P.) was a good example of",
A: "a mass party",
B: "an elite party",
C: "a tribal party",
D: "an international party",
answer: "A. a mass party",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Under the 1960 Republican Constitution of Ghana, the head of government was the",
A: "Chief Justice",
B: "Prime Minister",
C: "President",
D: "Governor",
answer: "C. President",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. A major problem confronting local authorities in Ghana is the",
A: "lack of qualified personnel",
B: "unclear boundary demarcation",
C: "presence of countless political conflicts",
D: "large number of local units",
answer: "A. lack of qualified personnel",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following controls public corporations in Ghana?",
A: "Public opinion",
B: "National house of chiefs",
C: "The army",
D: "The police",
answer: "A. Public opinion",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. An election which is conducted again between two presidential candidates because none of them secured the absolute majority Is called",
A: "cumulative vote system.",
B: "alternate vote system",
C: "Plurality systems.",
D: "Majoritarian systems.",
answer: "D. Majoritarian systems",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The system of political administration adopted by the British In their colonies was called",
A: "assimilation",
B: "Indirect rule",
C: "protectionism",
D: "laissez-faire",
answer: "B. Indirect rule",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The Food and Agriculture Organization ( FAO) Is a specialized agency of",
A: "Economic Community of West African States ( ECOWAS)",
B: "The Commonwealth of Nations",
C: "The Organization of African Unity ( OAU)",
D: "The United Nations Organization (UNO)",
answer: "D. The United Nations Organization (UNO)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following limits the sovereignty of a state?",
A: "Constituency delimitation",
B: "International law",
C: "Delegated legislation",
D: "Separation of Powers",
answer: "B. International law",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. An electoral commission performs the following functions except",
A: "adjudicating electoral malpractices & disputes",
B: "delimitation of constituency boundaries",
C: "installing polling booths",
D: "counting votes after elections",
answer: "A. adjudicating electoral malpractices & disputes",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The practice of judicial review makes invalid the principle of",
A: "individual responsibility",
B: "separation of powers",
C: "collective responsibility",
D: "delegated legislation",
answer: "B. separation of powers",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The pre-colonial West African constitutions were",
A: "flexible",
B: "rigid",
C: "written",
D: "unwritten",
answer: "A. flexible",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The main function of the executive in a state is the",
A: "adjudication of disputes",
B: "enforcement of the law",
C: "drafting of the constitution",
D: "registration of aliens",
answer: "B. enforcement of the law",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Trade Unions are examples of",
A: "tribal groups",
B: "elite parties",
C: "mass parties",
D: "pressure groups",
answer: "D. pressure groups",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The founder of communism is",
A: "General De Gaulle",
B: "Benito Mussolini",
C: "Karl Marx",
D: "Joseph Stalin .",
answer: "C. Karl Marx",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The Independence Constitution of Ghana was promulgated in",
A: "1992",
B: "1972",
C: "1960",
D: "197",
answer: "C. 1960",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The 1960 Republican Constitution of Ghana provided for a",
A: "president as the commander-in-chief of the armed forces",
B: "president as the chief justice",
C: "prime minister",
D: "bicameral legislature",
answer: "A. president as the commander-in-chief of the armed forces",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. A government under the control of the rich in a society is called",
A: "plutocracy",
B: "democracy",
C: "kakistocracy",
D: "monarchy",
answer: "A. plutocracy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The executive in a presidential system of government is headed by the",
A: "monarch",
B: "chief justice",
C: "prime minister",
D: "president",
answer: "D. president",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The pre-colonial political system in the Asante kingdom was.",
A: "acephalous",
B: "centralized",
C: "federal",
D: "confederal",
answer: "B. centralized",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The process of impeachment is an essential feature of the",
A: "Cabinet system of government",
B: "monarchical system of government",
C: "presidential system of government",
D: "conferral system of government",
answer: "C. presidential system of government",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. A constituency where more than two representatives are elected is called a",
A: "single-member constituency",
B: "Bi-member system of government",
C: "multi-member constituency",
D: "hexa-member constituency",
answer: "C. multi-member constituency",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The 1954 Frederick Bourne Commission of Enquiry recommended for Ghana a",
A: "federal system of government",
B: "Presidential system of government",
C: "Parliamentary system of government",
D: "Unitary system of government",
answer: "D. Unitary system of government",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. An aim of the National Congress of British West Africa ( NCBWA ) was the",
A: "establishment of a West Africa university",
B: "establishment of a West Africa high command",
C: "installation of a government controlled and directed by Africans",
D: "installation of a West African commercial bank.",
answer: "C. installation of a government controlled and directed by Africans",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. An important feature of the 1954 Constitution of Ghana was the",
A: "creation of a bicameral legislature",
B: "establishment of a federal government",
C: "introduction of the elective principle",
D: "granting of internal self-government",
answer: "D. granting of internal self-government",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question51",
question:  "51. In a cabinet system of government, the party which wins election",
A: "appoints a chief justice",
B: "enacts laws",
C: "forms a government",
D: "chooses the monarch",
answer: "C. forms a government",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question52",
question:  "52. All the following are organs of the United Nations Organization except the",
A: "Security Council",
B: "Trusteeship Council",
C: "International Court of Justice",
D: "Council of Ministers",
answer: "D. Council of Ministers",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question53",
question:  "53. The principle of judicial independence is practicable in a",
A: "totalitarian government",
B: "military government",
C: "democratic government",
D: "fascist government",
answer: "C. democratic government",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question54",
question:  "54. In which of the following systems of government are ceremonial and political powers usually fused ?",
A: "Parliamentary system of government",
B: "Presidential system of government",
C: "Unitary system of government",
D: "confederal system of government",
answer: "A. Parliamentary system of government",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question55",
question:  "55. The concept of separation of powers was propounded by",
A: "W. Mackenzie",
B: "V. Dicey",
C: "Harold Laski",
D: "Baron de Montesquieu",
answer: "D. Baron de Montesquieu",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question56",
question:  "56. In a monarchy, the head of state performs the following functions except",
A: "preparing the budget",
B: "pardoning offenders",
C: "appointing the prime minister",
D: "proroguing parliament",
answer: "A. preparing the budget",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question57",
question:  "57. The leadership of a one-party-state tends to be",
A: "democratic",
B: "benevolent",
C: "tyrannical",
D: "liberal",
answer: "C. tyrannical",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question58",
question:  "58. South Africa before 1994 was a good example of a",
A: "democratic state",
B: "fascist state",
C: "communist state",
D: "socialist state",
answer: "B. fascist state",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question59",
question:  "59. The number of non-permanent members on the Security Council of the United Nations Organization is",
A: "five",
B: "fifteen",
C: "ten",
D: "fifty-one",
answer: "C. ten",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question60",
question:  "60. A unitary system of government is one in which",
A: "political powers are concentrated at the centre",
B: "political powers are not centralized",
C: "one sovereign state is united with another",
D: "the centre and the units share equal political powers",
answer: "A. political powers are concentrated at the centre",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]